Evan Lu

evalu802@gmail.com | (510) 603-8737 | Alameda & Merced, CA | waffles-codes.github.io

SUMMARY

As a second-year Computer Science and Engineering student at UC Merced, I have hands-on experience coding robots for The Aztechs and developing professional web pages for both Neuroleap Corp and Conectado Inc. I excel in learning on the fly, problem solving, and adapting to new challenges. My strong communication skills and creativity are complemented by my attention to detail and self-motivation, driving me to continuously learn and innovate.

EDUCATION

Laney College - Oakland, CA-

Associate of Science - Computer Programming (Dual Enrolled in High School)

SEPTEMBER 2019 - JUNE 2023

- Weighted GPA: 4.58
- Relevant Education Experience: Object Oriented Programming in C++, Data Structures & Algorithms (Java), Microcomputer Assembly Language (x86 ASM & C++), Calculus I-III, Statistics

University of California, Merced - Merced, CA-

Bachelor of Science - Computer Science & Engineering

AUGUST 2023- CURRENT

- Cumulative GPA: 3.9
- Relevant Education Experience: Algorithm Design and Analysis (C++), Probability and Statistics (Python), Discrete Mathematics, Linear Algebra, Physics

EXPERIENCE

Conectado Inc. - Remote

I2G Intern

SEPTEMBER 2024 - CURRENT

- Developed and optimized algorithms to sort user recommendations by both relevance and alphabetically (React JS, Firebase)
- Collaborated with a team of interns to create a user ranking algorithm, integrate LinkedIn, and resolve general bugs

NeuroLeap Corp - Remote

Full Stack Intern

SEPTEMBER 2024 - CURRENT

- Developed and integrated solutions for efficient image loading from the SQL database based on user interactions
- Implemented try-catch blocks to prevent potential crashes, enhancing stability and user experience
- Enhanced the functionality and visual appeal of navigation menus by refining their structure

The Aztechs - Alameda, CA

Lead Programmer

SEPTEMBER 2021 - MAY 2023

- Programmed robots in Java (2021-22) and Kotlin (2022-23)
- Developed new methods using computer vision, gyros, and encoders for automatic robot aiming, balancing, and positioning
- Collaborated with mechanical and electrical teams
- Mentored junior team members in programming, Git usage, and general team collaboration

PROJECTS

Robot Hand

- Created a rock-paper-scissors robot using a Raspberry Pi, code on GitHub
- Integrated MediaPipe, machine learning, and OpenCV in Python, employing multi-core parallelization and low-level motor control
- Completed as a high school passion project, demonstrating advanced technical skills and problem-solving

NASA SpaceApps 2024 - Exosky!

- Global Nominee and Local Challenge Winner at UC Merced
- Developed a Python/Flask backend to process star data from the Gaia database and simulate the sky view from other planets
- Created a React frontend integrated with the Aladin Lite star map, allowing users to choose a planet and visualize its sky

SKILLS & AWARDS

- Programming: C++, Java, Kotlin, Python, React JS, MUI, Javascript, HTML, Git, x86 ASM, Linux CMD line
- Soft Skills: Always Learning, Attention to Detail, Critical Thinking, Communication, Collaboration, Adaptability, Analysis, Problem Solving, Technical, Self Motivation, Creativity, Public Speaking
- Interests: Robotics, Graphic Design, Video Creation, Arts & Crafts, Language Learning (programming or otherwise), Multiplayer Games
- Awards:
 - o Chancellor's Honor List & Dean's Honor List UC Merced
 - Academic Honor Student Peralta Community College District
 - Outstanding Student & Lifelong Learner Alameda Science and Technology Institute